<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating Linux VM to a Portable Live USB</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/clonevm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/clonevm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/11-7-linux/#tiny-11-ltsc-wtg-on-ventoy&#34;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ventoy.net/en/plugin_vtoyboot.html&#34;&gt;Creating Ventoy VDI for Linux Live USB&lt;/a&gt; , however, it may not boot on some strange hardware and I unfortunately have quite a few of those. So in such cases, it&amp;rsquo;s better to boot Linux natively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, we need &lt;a href=&#34;https://rescuezilla.com/&#34;&gt;Rescuezilla&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://clonezilla.org/&#34;&gt;Clonezilla&lt;/a&gt; to extract the Linux system out of Virtualbox&amp;rsquo;s hard drive (VDI/VMDK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download and load the ISO of Rescuezilla, a GUI version of Clonezilla, it&amp;rsquo;s larger but eaiser to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting Local LLMs (DeepSeek-R1) Easily with Harbor (Ollama&#43;Open-WebUI&#43;SearXNG)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, there is a need of private chatbot service as a complete alternative to OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s ChatGPT. So, I decide to implement one at home and make it accessible to everyone in my household alongside with my network printer and NAS (OpenMediaVault).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I used to recommend people using Llama series for English tasks and Qwen series for Chinese tasks. There was no open-source model that&amp;rsquo;s strong enough in multilingual tasks comparing to proprietary ones (GPT/Claude).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving ThinkCentre M58p in 2024</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/m58p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/m58p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Days before mini-PC become a thing, there was no NUC, MinisForum or Beelink. It was the time of thin client and SFF (small-form-factor), manufacturers such as Shuttle, Dell and Lenovo were made a lot of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, the performance of SoC was too weak so that even laptops wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use them. But my first dedicated home lab machine was an Atom D525, which was called embedded industrial computer. It served as a router rather than server due to its performance and heat. That was also the time when I got into the world of m0n0wall derivatives (pfSense/FreeNAS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Windows Nostalgia, Linux and Its Discontents</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/11-7-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/11-7-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-nostalgia&#34;&gt;Windows Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent video on Windows 7 as daily driver OS by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/RE08P0iqCzY&#34;&gt;Brodie Robertson&lt;/a&gt; was hilarious but also arguable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, XP is the best OS ever made by M$. However, it has became not so useful nowadays neither for retro gaming (which 98SE is the king) nor for day-to-day usage, due to both hardware and software incompatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compromise would be Windows 7. I agree there are too much of accumulated unpatched security vulnerabilities, but there are tricks to mitigate most of those either technically or strategically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on Windows via WSL2</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/wsl2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;wsl-installation&#34;&gt;WSL Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some special use cases where I would like to go through and show the process of setting up WSL. &lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ubuntu.com/wsl/en/latest/howto/install-ubuntu-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s official document&lt;/a&gt; works well on Windows 11 LTSC for WSL installation, there is also a tutorial from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/wsl2/&#34;&gt;sitepoint&lt;/a&gt; with more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing this on a double debloated version of Windows 11 from previous post of Tiny 11 WTG, where I downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli/releases&#34;&gt;WinGet&lt;/a&gt;, extracted &lt;code&gt;DesktopAppInstaller_Dependencies.zip&lt;/code&gt; and installed with PowerShell:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set up Monero Wallet Securely with Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I found myself with enough leisure and motivation to set up a crypto wallet. For my situation, investing time and money into my skills, knowledge, and projects yields more return and safer than in finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this time, I found some good VPN deals which I would like to pay with XMR. Plus it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to have some spare crypto in wallet  for making donations to my favorite creators and projects, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to set things up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USB Tethering a Portable Router into a Mobile WiFi Hotspot</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I came down to want a mobile hotspot when going out of home, something like Netgear Nighthawk M series, but able to flash custom firmware (OpenWrt/pfSense equivalents) and cheap. However, there is no such thing on the market even without budget consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it has to be done with DIY, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://OpenWrt.org/docs/guide-user/network/wan/smartphone.usb.tethering&#34;&gt;USB tethering with a router&lt;/a&gt;. In the case of tethering or so called Ethernet over USB, we are using a phone as a cellular modem for our router.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting RustDesk Server via Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/rustdesk-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/rustdesk-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk&#34;&gt;RustDesk&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite remote desktop tool which is the best alternative to any closed-source solutions, such as TeamViewer and Anydesk. It&amp;rsquo;s kinda like Bitwarden in the post-breach era of the cloud password manager (LastPass/1Password) market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a light user of RustDesk, I use it only occasionally. So I didn&amp;rsquo;t setup my own RD server on VPS even though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/rustdesk/comments/1cr8kfv/should_you_selfhost_a_rustdesk_server/&#34;&gt;I suppose to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, one of my RustDesk client got blocked to the official servers. So now I have enough reason to properly making it up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting Lip Syncing Deepfake Tools</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/lipsync/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/lipsync/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI-Generated content can be fun or &amp;ldquo;slop&amp;rdquo; according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2024/May/8/slop/&#34;&gt;Simon Willison&lt;/a&gt;, but also can be malevolent due to its abuse in phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my readers may have already known that recently I&amp;rsquo;m working on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.techshinobi.org/&#34;&gt;side project&lt;/a&gt; , which based on&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/appatalks/chatgpt-html&#34;&gt;chatgpt-html&lt;/a&gt; and uses LLMs to detect phishing emails. I think at some point, the tool should be able to detect phishing attempt from video content too. Because deepfake technology is so accessible nowadays and its generated content can be quite convincing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating ThinkPad C13 Yoga</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-update&#34;&gt;2024 Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrchromebox.tech/#home&#34;&gt;MrChromebox.tech&lt;/a&gt; had a major update a few month ago, so I decide to move on as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before that, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://clonezilla.org/&#34;&gt;Clonezilla&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;code&gt;rsync -aHAXS&lt;/code&gt; to back up the 32 GB emmc first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run in terminal, install &amp;ldquo;Full UEFI Firmware&amp;rdquo;
&lt;code&gt;cd; curl -LO mrchromebox.tech/firmware-util.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo bash firmware-util.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reboot, a full version of  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coreboot.org/&#34;&gt;coreboot&lt;/a&gt; is installed, by replacing the previous &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seabios.org/&#34;&gt;SeaBIOS&lt;/a&gt; which is partial and limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes this laptop now with a free firmware. A free GNU/Linux distro is needed to be reinstalled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Dive into Voice Cloning with SoftVC VITS and Bert-VITS2</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/voice-vits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/voice-vits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-deep-dive-into-voice-cloning-with-softvc-vits-and-bert-vits2&#34;&gt;A Deep Dive into Voice Cloning with SoftVC VITS and Bert-VITS2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapai/#tts-generation-webui&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I have tried a little bit of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rsxdalv/tts-generation-webui&#34;&gt;TTS Generation WebUI&lt;/a&gt; and found it&amp;rsquo;s interesting. So, I decide to train a usable model with my own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This voice cloning project explores both SVC for Voice Changing and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jaywalnut310/vits&#34;&gt;VITS&lt;/a&gt; for Text-to-Speech. There is no one tool does all jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tested several tools for this project. Many of the good guides, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SUC-DriverOld/so-vits-svc-Chinese-Detaild-Documents&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Hr4y197Cy&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yuque.com/umoubuton/ueupp5&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, are in Chinese. So, I thought it&amp;rsquo;s useful to post my notes in English.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheapskate&#39;s Homebrew AI Lab</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-stories&#34;&gt;Old Stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer hardware used to be more playful and worth tinkering. My favorate platfom from a decade ago, Sandy Bridge on LGA 1155, can still be powerful even today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the days, I used to repair people&amp;rsquo;s electronics for free. Because of that, I also received a lots of spares and e-waste in exchange. One of the best was a LGA 1155 motherboard with i5-2300 on it. Then, I bought a cheap E3-1245 and GTX 750 Ti to make it a gaming rig. I played a lot of games on that, such as Dark Souls series and Metro series. Before it was sold, last games I played on this build was Metro Exodus and Elden Ring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from Data Loss due to LUKS Failure</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-story&#34;&gt;Background Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I experienced a major data loss on my daily driver computer due to encryption failure. Last time I had encountered this sort of situation was over a decade ago with TrueCrypt on an external HDD and unfortunately lost everything that weren&amp;rsquo;t backed up. I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered everything from backup this time so I decide to document it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire storage on my daily driver is encrypted with LUKS and it suddenly fails on boot decryption. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the header backed up and have stopped using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/teejee2008/timeshift&#34;&gt;Timeshift&lt;/a&gt; for a long time due to it&amp;rsquo;s unschedulable which lead to chaotic performance impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Wisper Server with GUI using Generate-subtitles</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/gensub-whisper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/gensub-whisper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mayeaux/generate-subtitles&#34;&gt;Generate-subtitles &lt;/a&gt; as an alternative or substitute to YouTube closed captions (CC) since it does not always work as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating video contents, it comes very handy to have a high quality generated transcripts to start with. My favorite tools are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nikse.dk/subtitleedit&#34;&gt;Subtitle Edit&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aegisub.org/&#34;&gt;Aegisub&lt;/a&gt;. SE provides a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nikse.dk/subtitleedit/online&#34;&gt;online version&lt;/a&gt; and works with .SRT format which fits great into my Adobe Premiere Pro workflow. It also has built-in Auto Translation and Whisper support. Aegisub works with .ASS format which fits into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Kilo19/NixieVideoKit&#34;&gt;NixieVideoKit&lt;/a&gt; automated workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheapskate&#39;s Stable Diffusion Server</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapsd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-dall-e-no-midjourney-and-no-colab&#34;&gt;No DALL-E, No Midjourney and No Colab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a guide showing how to build your own stable diffusion server on what you already have or cheap used hardwares. It may not satisfy for a serious production use but pretty viable for learning, testing or casual use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start, here&amp;rsquo;s some comments on OpenAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/history-of-openai-company-chatgpt-elon-musk-founded-2022-12&#34;&gt;The history of ChatGPT creator OpenAI, which Elon Musk helped found before parting ways and criticizing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vice.com/en/article/5d3naz/openai-is-now-everything-it-promised-not-to-be-corporate-closed-source-and-for-profit&#34;&gt;OpenAI Is Now Everything It Promised Not to Be: Corporate, Closed-Source, and For-Profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scribe.nixnet.services/geekculture/will-chatgpt-be-open-source-4b2928d57a2&#34;&gt;Will ChatGPT be open source?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.com/2023/03/24/column/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT, how did you get here? It was a long journey through open source AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tcrn.ch/3MKBD5P&#34;&gt;When big AI labs refuse to open source their models, the community steps in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Sqa8Zo2XWc4&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence: Last Week Tonight with John Oliver (HBO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hZTv-R6E32Y&#34;&gt;The TRUTH about OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using ChatGPT and its API regulary. Since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/bypass-chatgpt/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, the API has been upgraded to gpt-3.5-turbo which broke my program and gpt-4 seems coming up soon. Therefore, I may not fix my code proactively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N900, postmarketOS and Ideology</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;0x00-before-start&#34;&gt;0x00 Before Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I just gave my iPhone 4S away. This phone runs smoothly with jailbreak iOS 6.1.3. It was siting in my nostalgia box for years and has never been my daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in time, I was a big fun of Motorola Milestone/Droid series and my main phone was the last of these QWERTY phones, Photon Q (XT897). Its keyboard was fantastic and CyanogenMod 11 (Android 4.4 KitKat) with XPosed framework was perfect in both productivity and aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kali and Anonsurf</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kali-linux--freshtomato&#34;&gt;Kali Linux &amp;amp; FreshTomato&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parrot OS was on my old ThinkPad for many years. I recently upgraded it and had some issue with my multi-bootloader. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not Parrot OS&amp;rsquo;s fault, I switched to Kali Linux as a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this pentesting system since early BackTrack era but never felt it ought to be installed on a hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphic installer is much simpler than Parrot OS that may not be an issue for most people. My complain is just because my multi-boot hard drive has a very complex partition structure where an advanced installer is needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge TTS Reader</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-the-command-line&#34;&gt;Back to the Command-line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, MS Edge for Linux does not have the Read Aloud feature which is the only reason I would like to use Edge. The TTS engine made by Microsoft sounds incomparable to those poorly made chrome extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I found a work around with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rany2/edge-tts&#34;&gt;edge-tts&lt;/a&gt;. This is a CLI tool uses Edge TTS service. The instruction on its Github repo is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installation, use &lt;code&gt;edge-tts --list-voices | grep US&lt;/code&gt; to show English speaking characters and now I can locate a text file in the terminal to be read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Mouse</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acceleration&#34;&gt;Acceleration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my teenage years, I was really into FPS and RTS games. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m kind of picky on computer mouses and being paranoid of acceleration in the OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permanently disabling acceleration for Windows is simple. Besides unchecking the &amp;ldquo;Enhance pointer precision&amp;rdquo; in the &lt;code&gt;main.cpl&lt;/code&gt;, some registry hacks such as the good old classic &amp;ldquo;CPL Mouse Fix&amp;rdquo; or the later &amp;ldquo;MarkC&amp;rdquo; would do it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esreality.com/?a=post&amp;amp;id=1846538&#34;&gt;easily by a REG/batch file&lt;/a&gt;. It is also possible &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcgamingwiki.com/wiki/Glossary:Mouse_acceleration&#34;&gt;doing manually&lt;/a&gt; if you want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
