<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making N100 mini-PC into a pfSense Box</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/n100pfsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/n100pfsense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I was a teenager, I have started voluntarily helping people around me with my skill of technology. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m helping someone to build up a robust, secure and cost-effective firewall/gateway/soft router at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ends up on a $100 worth N100 mini-pc with dual Ethernet port, which can be a great pfSense box for home or even business use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-tweaks&#34;&gt;Hardware Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model (T8PLUS) secured with 4 screws at outside, after removing them the outer case can be easily pried open (just a little bit more effort than Intel NUCs), and removing 4 more screws inside to get the access of the motherboard (way more simpler design of the power button comparing to NUCs).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing YouTube IP block with FreeTube and optimized Tor</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/ytproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/ytproxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, YouTube is messing with user disobedience again. For the sake of that, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FreeTubeApp/FreeTube&#34;&gt;FreeTube&lt;/a&gt; has been updating with fix multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although FreeTube has fixed the API block done by YouTube, I have to deal with a new IP block from my end as its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;YouTube has blocked your IP address from watching videos. Please try switching to a different VPN or proxy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get around this IP block. Because I think switching VPN server is too heavy just for this, I would like to use a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Security with Documents</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/opsecdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/opsecdocs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I started sending/receiving documents to/from untrusted sources. In my threat model, this requires extra operational security to prevent privacy exposure and security risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/freedomofpress/dangerzone/blob/main/INSTALL.md#windows&#34;&gt;offical guide&lt;/a&gt; is not so detailed for Windows, I decided to write one while installing on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/tiny11wtg/#windows-11-ltsc-double-debloat&#34;&gt;Windows 11 LTSC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, in Windows Terminal/PowerShell, run &lt;code&gt;wsl --install&lt;/code&gt; to setup WSL2. Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/wsl2/&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the latest verisons of Dangerzone 0.9.1 and docker desktop 4.44.3 have unsolvable bug (reports &lt;code&gt;unknown error &#39;2&#39;&lt;/code&gt;), I have to choose the ealier version which works properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My AI Learning Materials and News Feeds (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forewords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd time updating the lists, where I added a section of Prompt Engineering upon requests since it is a good starting point for those not into self-hosting nor theory. The term &amp;ldquo;Prompt Engineering&amp;rdquo; is a bit controversial but people will get better understanding after learning the listed materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong self-learner, I use all sorts of methods to learn new things, and AI is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently into. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AI tools since 2022, my background wasn&amp;rsquo;t focused on AI. So, like everyone else, I had to do some &amp;ldquo;AI For Dummies&amp;rdquo; level study in order to get more involved. Below is a list of learning materials that I find very helpful for myself to get started with and might also be helpful for someone else in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set up Monero Wallet Securely with Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I found myself with enough leisure and motivation to set up a crypto wallet. For my situation, investing time and money into my skills, knowledge, and projects yields more return and safer than in finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this time, I found some good VPN deals which I would like to pay with XMR. Plus it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to have some spare crypto in wallet  for making donations to my favorite creators and projects, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to set things up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USB Tethering a Portable Router into a Mobile WiFi Hotspot</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I came down to want a mobile hotspot when going out of home, something like Netgear Nighthawk M series, but able to flash custom firmware (OpenWrt/pfSense equivalents) and cheap. However, there is no such thing on the market even without budget consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it has to be done with DIY, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://OpenWrt.org/docs/guide-user/network/wan/smartphone.usb.tethering&#34;&gt;USB tethering with a router&lt;/a&gt;. In the case of tethering or so called Ethernet over USB, we are using a phone as a cellular modem for our router.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from Data Loss due to LUKS Failure</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-story&#34;&gt;Background Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I experienced a major data loss on my daily driver computer due to encryption failure. Last time I had encountered this sort of situation was over a decade ago with TrueCrypt on an external HDD and unfortunately lost everything that weren&amp;rsquo;t backed up. I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered everything from backup this time so I decide to document it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire storage on my daily driver is encrypted with LUKS and it suddenly fails on boot decryption. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the header backed up and have stopped using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/teejee2008/timeshift&#34;&gt;Timeshift&lt;/a&gt; for a long time due to it&amp;rsquo;s unschedulable which lead to chaotic performance impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
