<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Learning Materials for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</guid>
      <description>AI Learning Materials for Everyone As a lifelong self-learner, I use all sorts of methods to learn new things, and AI is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently into. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the game since 2022, my background wasn&amp;rsquo;t focused on AI. So, like everyone else, I had to do some &amp;ldquo;AI For Dummies&amp;rdquo; level study in order to get more involved. Below is a list of learning materials that I find very helpful for myself to get started with and might also be helpful for someone else in the same situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up Monero Wallet Securely with Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</guid>
      <description>Eventually, I found myself with enough leisure and motivation to set up a crypto wallet. For my situation, investing time and money into my skills, knowledge, and projects yields more return and safer than in finance.
But in this time, I found some good VPN deals which I would like to pay with XMR. Plus it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to have some spare crypto in wallet for making donations to my favorite creators and projects, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to set things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Tethering a Portable Router into a Mobile WiFi Hotspot</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tethering-hotspot/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came down to want a mobile hotspot when going out of home, something like Netgear Nighthawk M series, but able to flash custom firmware (OpenWrt/pfSense equivalents) and cheap. However, there is no such thing on the market even without budget consideration.
So it has to be done with DIY, like USB tethering with a router. In the case of tethering or so called Ethernet over USB, we are using a phone as a cellular modem for our router.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from Data Loss due to LUKS Failure</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/recoverluks/</guid>
      <description>Background Story Last week, I experienced a major data loss on my daily driver computer due to encryption failure. Last time I had encountered this sort of situation was over a decade ago with TrueCrypt on an external HDD and unfortunately lost everything that weren&amp;rsquo;t backed up. I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered everything from backup this time so I decide to document it.
The entire storage on my daily driver is encrypted with LUKS and it suddenly fails on boot decryption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
