<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mind on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mind on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flashing DD-WRT into a Linksys MR7350 with Basic Hardening</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/ddwrt-mr7350/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/ddwrt-mr7350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since my WiFi is getting more and more unstable, and I finally decided to retire my NETGEAR R6300v2 which has served me well since in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was in used condition when I bought it, so this is a good time to get a &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the ISPs in my area are very bad, I still have to stick with the low speed Internet for probably quite some time. So I decided to buy a used &lt;a href=&#34;https://wikidevi.wi-cat.ru/Linksys_MR7350&#34;&gt;Linksys MR7350&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The HackerNoon Problems</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/hackernoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/hackernoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To boost my article visibility on the fractured internet, reposting to larger platforms is my strategy to grow and HackerNoon has been my choice for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this platform is a boat which sinks even faster than Medium. I have been rejected arbitrarily by the editor earlier this year just for minor formatting improvements, which is still tolerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, they not only rejected my submission, but also banned me from the platform for no reason whatsoever. I can&amp;rsquo;t find any information in my Inbox, notifications or anywhere else. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m trying to edit or write a post, I get a red warning saying &amp;ldquo;You have been banned&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating EPUB from Scanned PDF with MinerU and LLMs</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/mineru/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/mineru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a book reader, I read over a hundred books each year and collect much more. The preferred format is absolutely EPUB, however, I can&amp;rsquo;t always get books in EPUB/MOBI especially for rare or old books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, they are available in PDF if at all. Some of these PDFs are manually scanned in a barely readable condition. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t blame on them since &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/opsecdocs/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing that before&lt;/a&gt; and know that is not easy. What I need is a tool to convert the not so readable book into a readable one with OCR and LLM, that is MinerU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Video Resolution and Frame Rate with video2x</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/video2x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/video2x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I downloaded an old documentary made in early 2000s. The original resolution was 854×480 with a less than 1000 KB/S bitrate. Because I like the content so there is enough reason to enhance my watching experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download installer instead of the zip pack from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/k4yt3x/video2x/releases/&#34;&gt;k4yt3x&amp;rsquo;s github repo&lt;/a&gt;, this will install all binaries and dependencies for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After restart the system, open video2x and load a video, it can automatically detect the GPU if it exists. Gaming GPU with higher frequency/hashrate is preferred over larger VRAM in this case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My AI Learning Materials and News Feeds (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forewords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd time updating the lists, where I added a section of Prompt Engineering upon requests since it is a good starting point for those not into self-hosting nor theory. The term &amp;ldquo;Prompt Engineering&amp;rdquo; is a bit controversial but people will get better understanding after learning the listed materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong self-learner, I use all sorts of methods to learn new things, and AI is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently into. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AI tools since 2022, my background wasn&amp;rsquo;t focused on AI. So, like everyone else, I had to do some &amp;ldquo;AI For Dummies&amp;rdquo; level study in order to get more involved. Below is a list of learning materials that I find very helpful for myself to get started with and might also be helpful for someone else in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating VMs from ESXi to Proxmox VE</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/migratevm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/migratevm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m doing this. In the days when Virtual Machine was the thing, VMware Workstation was the go-to option for a Windows host to run VMs. We have to find cracked version for personal use, since there was no VirtualBox neither Hyper-V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, when I first decided to have a proper homelab in my household, I went blindly into ESXi just because VMware Workstation has already installed on all of my computers. Although I was pretty like Proxmox during that time, it was considered for not so serious projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On iPhone, Design and Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-talks&#34;&gt;iPhone Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a many cellphones that make me feel nostalgic. None of them is Android nor iPhone. Some of them are &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/&#34;&gt;QWERTY&lt;/a&gt;, some are flip phones. Phones were much interesting back in the days when Motorola, Nokia, Sony, Sharp, Blackberry and more are still competitive in the market. Today&amp;rsquo;s smartphones are indifferent and rather being &amp;ldquo;boredphones&amp;rdquo;. And all of these boredness are rooted in the &amp;ldquo;iPhone Moment&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite how much I dislike iPhone&amp;rsquo;s disruptive innovation and its market breakthrough as well as Apple&amp;rsquo;s philosophy behind it. There is one thing true about the spirit of Steve Jobs, that is, a phone should be comfortably used in one hand. Although this was his defense of iPhone&amp;rsquo;s 3.5 inch screen size, I strongly agree with his ergonomics minded UX design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving ThinkCentre M58p in 2024</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/m58p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/m58p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Days before mini-PC become a thing, there was no NUC, MinisForum or Beelink. It was the time of thin client and SFF (small-form-factor), manufacturers such as Shuttle, Dell and Lenovo were made a lot of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, the performance of SoC was too weak so that even laptops wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use them. But my first dedicated home lab machine was an Atom D525, which was called embedded industrial computer. It served as a router rather than server due to its performance and heat. That was also the time when I got into the world of m0n0wall derivatives (pfSense/FreeNAS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Windows Nostalgia, Linux and Its Discontents</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/11-7-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/11-7-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-nostalgia&#34;&gt;Windows Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent video on Windows 7 as daily driver OS by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/RE08P0iqCzY&#34;&gt;Brodie Robertson&lt;/a&gt; was hilarious but also arguable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, XP is the best OS ever made by M$. However, it has became not so useful nowadays neither for retro gaming (which 98SE is the king) nor for day-to-day usage, due to both hardware and software incompatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compromise would be Windows 7. I agree there are too much of accumulated unpatched security vulnerabilities, but there are tricks to mitigate most of those either technically or strategically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheapskate&#39;s NAS Migration from Unraid to Openmediavault</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapnas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cheapskates-nas-migration-from-unraid-to-openmediavault&#34;&gt;Cheapskate&amp;rsquo;s NAS Migration from Unraid to Openmediavault&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, I come across a lot of abandoned computers and recycled parts out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is about the recycled &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapai/#old-stories&#34;&gt;Dell Vostro 220s with LGA771 to LGA775 Mod&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned in the last post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was running Unraid with a low power Xeon L5410 and 2 GB of RAM for many years. The only repair was a PSU replacement two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI CyberSecurity, ChatGPT and Post-humanism</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the text for a lecture I&amp;rsquo;m going to give recently. Thanks for &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielabaron.me/blog/build-and-publish-presentation-with-html-and-css/&#34;&gt;Daniela Baron&amp;rsquo;s guide&lt;/a&gt; which helped me tremendously for creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/AI-CyberSec-PH-presentation/&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js/&#34;&gt;RevealJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone. Well, first, I have to confess and apologize that I could not prepare this enough. Because I have to working on my dissertation, which also discusses about AI augmented APT attack such as using ChatGPT to create phishing email and ransomware code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if anyone is interested in that direction, but I digressed, let&amp;rsquo;s get to start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started This Blog</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-this-day-and-age&#34;&gt;In This Day and Age?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, when MySpace and 000webhost was the thing. I wrote blog regularly about my life and hobby. That was the beginning of my Internet journey and tweaking CSS code while posting an article was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to post my stuff on somewhere like mastodon or telegram channel but here I am. Because I feel most comfortable this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dilemma-of-giving-back&#34;&gt;Dilemma of Giving Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of my Linux journey was with some early version of OpenWrt and BackTrack, then Puppy and Ubuntu. At this very moment, I&amp;rsquo;m typing with MarkText on a Pop!_OS and all my servers are running on either CentOS or Debian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
