<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Server on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/tags/server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Server on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/tags/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting Local LLMs (DeepSeek-R1) Easily with Harbor (Ollama&#43;Open-WebUI&#43;SearXNG)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, there is a need of private chatbot service as a complete alternative to OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s ChatGPT. So, I decide to implement one at home and make it accessible to everyone in my household alongside with my network printer and NAS (OpenMediaVault).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I used to recommend people using Llama series for English tasks and Qwen series for Chinese tasks. There was no open-source model that&amp;rsquo;s strong enough in multilingual tasks comparing to proprietary ones (GPT/Claude).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting RustDesk Server via Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/rustdesk-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/rustdesk-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk&#34;&gt;RustDesk&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite remote desktop tool which is the best alternative to any closed-source solutions, such as TeamViewer and Anydesk. It&amp;rsquo;s kinda like Bitwarden in the post-breach era of the cloud password manager (LastPass/1Password) market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a light user of RustDesk, I use it only occasionally. So I didn&amp;rsquo;t setup my own RD server on VPS even though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/rustdesk/comments/1cr8kfv/should_you_selfhost_a_rustdesk_server/&#34;&gt;I suppose to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, one of my RustDesk client got blocked to the official servers. So now I have enough reason to properly making it up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
