<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My AI Learning Materials and News Feeds (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/learn-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forewords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd time updating the lists, where I added a section of Prompt Engineering upon requests since it is a good starting point for those not into self-hosting nor theory. The term &amp;ldquo;Prompt Engineering&amp;rdquo; is a bit controversial but people will get better understanding after learning the listed materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong self-learner, I use all sorts of methods to learn new things, and AI is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently into. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AI tools since 2022, my background wasn&amp;rsquo;t focused on AI. So, like everyone else, I had to do some &amp;ldquo;AI For Dummies&amp;rdquo; level study in order to get more involved. Below is a list of learning materials that I find very helpful for myself to get started with and might also be helpful for someone else in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with the Enshittification of ProtonVPN&#39;s Free Plan (WireGuard&#43;NextDNS)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/proton-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/proton-shit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is originally composed on 2024-11-28. I&amp;rsquo;m updating it for combining NextDNS, since I have started using a new freemium app with nasty ADs in it. ProtonVPN&amp;rsquo;s free plan doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to configure AD blocking DNS, especially with their official app. But with WireGuard app, this can be trivial. Thank to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/ProtonVPN/comments/15x7q1q/guide_nextdns_proton_vpn_wireguard_doh3_on_ios&#34;&gt;original guide on reddit&lt;/a&gt;, the newly added part is in the end of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a early adopter of Protonmail, I use their later coming VPN product as well, regularly yet lightly. Although I&amp;rsquo;m a potential customer but still not paying for any of their plan, for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On iPhone, Design and Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-talks&#34;&gt;iPhone Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a many cellphones that make me feel nostalgic. None of them is Android nor iPhone. Some of them are &lt;a href=&#34;https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/&#34;&gt;QWERTY&lt;/a&gt;, some are flip phones. Phones were much interesting back in the days when Motorola, Nokia, Sony, Sharp, Blackberry and more are still competitive in the market. Today&amp;rsquo;s smartphones are indifferent and rather being &amp;ldquo;boredphones&amp;rdquo;. And all of these boredness are rooted in the &amp;ldquo;iPhone Moment&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite how much I dislike iPhone&amp;rsquo;s disruptive innovation and its market breakthrough as well as Apple&amp;rsquo;s philosophy behind it. There is one thing true about the spirit of Steve Jobs, that is, a phone should be comfortably used in one hand. Although this was his defense of iPhone&amp;rsquo;s 3.5 inch screen size, I strongly agree with his ergonomics minded UX design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
