<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Wisper Server with GUI using Generate-subtitles</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/gensub-whisper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/gensub-whisper/</guid>
      <description>I use Generate-subtitles  as an alternative or substitute to YouTube closed captions (CC) since it does not always work as expected.
When creating video contents, it comes very handy to have a high quality generated transcripts to start with. My favorite tools are Subtitle Edit and Aegisub. SE provides a great online version and works with .SRT format which fits great into my Adobe Premiere Pro workflow. It also has built-in Auto Translation and Whisper support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI CyberSecurity, ChatGPT and Post-humanism</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</guid>
      <description>This is the text for a lecture I&amp;rsquo;m going to give recently. Thanks for Daniela Baron&amp;rsquo;s guide which helped me tremendously for creating the slides with RevealJS.
Hey everyone. Well, first, I have to confess and apologize that I could not prepare this enough. Because I have to working on my dissertation, which also discusses about AI augmented APT attack such as using ChatGPT to create phishing email and ransomware code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheapskate&#39;s Stable Diffusion Server</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/cheapsd/</guid>
      <description>No DALL-E, No Midjourney and No Colab This is a guide showing how to build your own stable diffusion server on what you already have or cheap used hardwares. It may not satisfy for a serious production use but pretty viable for learning, testing or casual use.
Before we start, here&amp;rsquo;s some comments on OpenAI:
 The history of ChatGPT creator OpenAI, which Elon Musk helped found before parting ways and criticizing OpenAI Is Now Everything It Promised Not to Be: Corporate, Closed-Source, and For-Profit Will ChatGPT be open source?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing ChatGPT&#39;s Safeguard and Easiest Way to use API</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/bypass-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/bypass-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>The latest news updated on waylaidwanderer&amp;rsquo;s repo says:
 2023-02-15 The method we were using to access the ChatGPT raw models has been patched, unfortunately.
 Therefore, the party is over. It was fun to play with those leaked models such as text-davinci-002-render, text-chat-davinci-002-20221122, and text-chat-davinci-002-sh-alpha-aoruigiofdj83. They&amp;rsquo;re not as good as the official model text-davinci-003 after all as my previous post said.
Why use API instead of the Ordinary Way After OpenAI fired up their paid subscription for ChatGPT, availability issue like response error, rate limit and throttling become more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Different GPT-3 and ChatGPT models</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/playing-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/playing-gpt/</guid>
      <description>The Original Flavors In OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s documentation there are 4 models under GPT-3 category and 2 coding models. They cost from $0.02 to $0.0004 per 1k tokens as the base model and the fine-tuned versions cost even more.
 text-davinci-003 text-curie-001 text-babbage-001 text-ada-001 code-davinci-002 code-cushman-001  The playground can test them all using the web interface.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how good they are comparing to the free ChatGPT.
To ChatGPT webpage: Who is Paul Graham?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unblock URLs from My Own Filter Lists</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/unblock-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/unblock-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Podcast doesn&amp;rsquo;t fetch I have multiple devices that are using different URL based filter methods. Some are at the router level and some are at the system level, e.g., Hosts file, DNS and VPN built-in.
Recently, I found out there is a broken one in my podcast subscriptions.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time not listening to the podcast, Startups For the Rest of Us, since I started following Rob Walling&amp;rsquo;s new show called MicroConf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with ThinkPad C13 Yoga</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a new ThinkPad which took Lenovo over 2 month preparing for shipping. For the price, it worth waiting. This is the first Chromebook I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had, so I did quite a lot experiments with it.
Hardware The model is C13 Yoga Chromebook (MORPHIUS) with AMD Athlon gold 3015c (Picasso) 4GB RAM and 32GB eMMc storage.
There are multiple variations in C13 models and mine is the lowest-end of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N900, postmarketOS and Ideology</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/pmos/</guid>
      <description>0x00 Before Start Recently, I just gave my iPhone 4S away. This phone runs smoothly with jailbreak iOS 6.1.3. It was siting in my nostalgia box for years and has never been my daily driver.
Back in time, I was a big fun of Motorola Milestone/Droid series and my main phone was the last of these QWERTY phones, Photon Q (XT897). Its keyboard was fantastic and CyanogenMod 11 (Android 4.4 KitKat) with XPosed framework was perfect in both productivity and aesthetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kali and Anonsurf</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</guid>
      <description>Kali Linux &amp;amp; FreshTomato Parrot OS was on my old ThinkPad for many years. I recently upgraded it and had some issue with my multi-bootloader. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not Parrot OS&amp;rsquo;s fault, I switched to Kali Linux as a workaround.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this pentesting system since early BackTrack era but never felt it ought to be installed on a hard drive.
The graphic installer is much simpler than Parrot OS that may not be an issue for most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge TTS Reader</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</guid>
      <description>Back to the Command-line For some reason, MS Edge for Linux does not have the Read Aloud feature which is the only reason I would like to use Edge. The TTS engine made by Microsoft sounds incomparable to those poorly made chrome extensions.
Therefore, I found a work around with edge-tts. This is a CLI tool uses Edge TTS service. The instruction on its Github repo is very good.
After installation, use edge-tts --list-voices | grep US to show English speaking characters and now I can locate a text file in the terminal to be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Mouse</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</guid>
      <description>Acceleration During my teenage years, I was really into FPS and RTS games. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m kind of picky on computer mouses and being paranoid of acceleration in the OS.
Permanently disabling acceleration for Windows is simple. Besides unchecking the &amp;ldquo;Enhance pointer precision&amp;rdquo; in the main.cpl, some registry hacks such as the good old classic &amp;ldquo;CPL Mouse Fix&amp;rdquo; or the later &amp;ldquo;MarkC&amp;rdquo; would do it easily by a REG/batch file. It is also possible doing manually if you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Things Behind This Website</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</guid>
      <description>#aliases: [&amp;ldquo;standby&amp;rdquo;] This is my 2nd time using HUGO and hosting a site on Github Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s so convenient compare to self hosting. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to set up DDNS or CDN, also not have to patch up or update everything periodically to keep it secure.
All the steps I have done are very similar to this article, except making the Personal Access Token and Custom Domain (these are easy to find separately).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started This Blog</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</guid>
      <description>In This Day and Age? Back then, when MySpace and 000webhost was the thing. I wrote blog regularly about my life and hobby. That was the beginning of my Internet journey and tweaking CSS code while posting an article was fun.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to post my stuff on somewhere like mastodon or telegram channel but here I am. Because I feel most comfortable this way.
Dilemma of Giving Back The beginning of my Linux journey was with some early version of OpenWrt and BackTrack, then Puppy and Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
