<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kali and Anonsurf</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</guid>
      <description>Kali Linux &amp;amp; FreshTomato Parrot OS was on my old ThinkPad for many years. I recently upgraded it and had some issue with my multi-bootloader. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not Parrot OS&amp;rsquo;s fault, I switched to Kali Linux as a workaround.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this pentesting system since early BackTrack era but never felt it ought to be installed on a hard drive.
The graphic installer is much simpler than Parrot OS that may not be an issue for most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge TTS Reader</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/edgetts/</guid>
      <description>Back to the Command-line For some reason, MS Edge for Linux does not have the Read Aloud feature which is the only reason I would like to use Edge. The TTS engine made by Microsoft sounds incomparable to those poorly made chrome extensions.
Therefore, I found a work around with edge-tts. This is a CLI tool uses Edge TTS service. The instruction on its Github repo is very good.
After installation, use edge-tts --list-voices | grep US to show English speaking characters and now I can locate a text file in the terminal to be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Mouse</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tweakingmouse/</guid>
      <description>Acceleration During my teenage years, I was really into FPS and RTS games. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m kind of picky on computer mouses and being paranoid of acceleration in the OS.
Permanently disabling acceleration for Windows is simple. Besides unchecking the &amp;ldquo;Enhance pointer precision&amp;rdquo; in the main.cpl, some registry hacks such as the good old classic &amp;ldquo;CPL Mouse Fix&amp;rdquo; or the later &amp;ldquo;MarkC&amp;rdquo; would do it easily by a REG/batch file. It is also possible doing manually if you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Things Behind This Website</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</guid>
      <description>This is my 2nd time using HUGO and hosting a site on Github Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s so convenient compare to self hosting. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to set up DDNS or CDN, also not have to patch up or update everything periodically to keep it secure.
All the steps I have done are very similar to this article, except making the Personal Access Token and Custom Domain (these are easy to find separately).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started This Blog</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/why-i-started/</guid>
      <description>In This Day and Age? Back then, when MySpace and 000webhost was the thing. I wrote blog regularly about my life and hobby. That was the beginning of my Internet journey and tweaking CSS code while posting an article was fun.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to post my stuff on somewhere like mastodon or telegram channel but here I am. Because I feel most comfortable this way.
Dilemma of Giving Back The beginning of my Linux journey was with some early version of OpenWrt and BackTrack, then Puppy and Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
