<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Tech Shinobi</title>
    <link>https://techshinobi.org/categories/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Tech Shinobi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techshinobi.org/categories/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting Local LLMs (DeepSeek-R1) Easily with Harbor (Ollama&#43;Open-WebUI&#43;SearXNG)</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/easy-local-llm/</guid>
      <description>Lately, there is a need of private chatbot service as a complete alternative to OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s ChatGPT. So, I decide to implement one at home and make it accessible to everyone in my household alongside with my network printer and NAS (OpenMediaVault).
In the past, I used to recommend others using Llama series for English tasks and Qwen series for Chinese tasks. There were no open-source model that strong enough in multilingual tasks comparing to proprietary ones (GPT/Claude).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up Monero Wallet Securely with Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/menero-wallet/</guid>
      <description>Eventually, I found myself with enough leisure and motivation to set up a crypto wallet. For my situation, investing time and money into my skills, knowledge, and projects yields more return and safer than in finance.
But in this time, I found some good VPN deals which I would like to pay with XMR. Plus it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to have some spare crypto in wallet for making donations to my favorite creators and projects, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to set things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with the Enshittification of Proton VPN on Free Plan&#39;s Server Selection</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/proton-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/proton-shit/</guid>
      <description>As a early adopter of Protonmail, I use their later coming VPN product as well, regularly yet lightly. Although I&amp;rsquo;m a potential customer but still not paying for any of their plan, for many reasons.
Being a free account user, I&amp;rsquo;ve never done torrenting or any other heavy usage on their servers. It is not moral even though the provider allows me to.
Probably because of my account was old enough so that my country selection feature wasn&amp;rsquo;t banned until latest update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating ThinkPad C13 Yoga</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/tpc13/</guid>
      <description>2024 Update MrChromebox.tech had a major update a few month ago, so I decide to move on as well.
But before that, use Clonezilla or rsync -aHAXS to back up the 32 GB emmc first.
Run in terminal, install &amp;ldquo;Full UEFI Firmware&amp;rdquo; cd; curl -LO mrchromebox.tech/firmware-util.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo bash firmware-util.sh
After reboot, a full version of coreboot is installed, by replacing the previous SeaBIOS which is partial and limited.
This makes this laptop now with a free firmware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dehaunting OnePlus Nord N30 5G</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/opn30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/opn30/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I bought a Metro locked Oneplus Nord N30 5G (CPH2513/CPH2515) for $60 during a very slick deal.
However, this phone was completely unusable due to it is haunted with tons of bloatware and spyware. So I decided to let it sit in a drawer for 180 days and then see what I can do with it.
A few days ago, I unlocked it by simply go to About Phone then click Unlock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI CyberSecurity, ChatGPT and Post-humanism</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/aisecph/</guid>
      <description>This is the text for a lecture I&amp;rsquo;m going to give recently. Thanks for Daniela Baron&amp;rsquo;s guide which helped me tremendously for creating the slides with RevealJS.
Hey everyone. Well, first, I have to confess and apologize that I could not prepare this enough. Because I have to working on my dissertation, which also discusses about AI augmented APT attack such as using ChatGPT to create phishing email and ransomware code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unblock URLs from My Own Filter Lists</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/unblock-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/unblock-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Podcast doesn&amp;rsquo;t fetch I have multiple devices that are using different URL based filter methods. Some are at the router level and some are at the system level, e.g., Hosts file, DNS and VPN built-in.
Recently, I found out there is a broken one in my podcast subscriptions.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time not listening to the podcast, Startups For the Rest of Us, since I started following Rob Walling&amp;rsquo;s new show called MicroConf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kali and Anonsurf</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/kalianon/</guid>
      <description>Kali Linux &amp;amp; FreshTomato Parrot OS was on my old ThinkPad for many years. I recently upgraded it and had some issue with my multi-bootloader. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not Parrot OS&amp;rsquo;s fault, I switched to Kali Linux as a workaround.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this pentesting system since early BackTrack era but never felt it ought to be installed on a hard drive.
The graphic installer is much simpler than Parrot OS that may not be an issue for most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Things Behind This Website</title>
      <link>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techshinobi.org/posts/little-things-behind/</guid>
      <description>#aliases: [&amp;ldquo;standby&amp;rdquo;] This is my 2nd time using HUGO and hosting a site on Github Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s so convenient compare to self hosting. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to set up DDNS or CDN, also not have to patch up or update everything periodically to keep it secure.
All the steps I have done are very similar to this article, except making the Personal Access Token and Custom Domain (these are easy to find separately).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
